do do do you see how how we we sniped we
got Joel on a path and now Joel has gone
to a different CSP now Joel's looking at
the code of the CSP evaluator during by
the end of this episode I'm gonna have a
CSP
evaluator techno geek. CSP evaluator
let's go
[Music]
[Applause]
hey everyone this is techno geek here
just wanted to give a quick shout out to
our latest sponsor project Discovery now
project Discovery makes a lot of tools
that you probably know of or have even
used uh one of them is nuclei and the
latest release of nuclei is version 3.2
now 3.2 comes with a lot of really
awesome new features um two that I
really wanted to highlight here for you
are the authenticated scanning and the
advanced fuzzing support now for
authenticated scanning it used to be
that you would have to do all your
nuclei scanning against unauthenticated
end points or you'd have to add your
cookies manually all that kind of messy
no more it's all automatic you can use
existing login templates to
automatically log in to your application
and then you can run all your existing
nuclei templates against an
authenticated part of the application
now to really increase your coverage uh
the other that I mentioned is Advanced
fuzzing support now nuclea had added way
back in version 2.8 the ability to fuzz
different things but now they've
expanded this comprehensively across the
board so not only can you fuzz in the
normal spots but you can fuzz within
headers you can fuzz within cookies you
can fuzz within specific parts of the
body whether that's in Json or XML or
form data and so many more things so if
you want to learn more about what came
in nuclei 3.2 go ahead and check out the
the release blog post over at nu. g/p
podcast that's nx. g/p podcast
thanks yo Yan welcome to the Pod man
thank you very excited to have you on we
um I wanted so the reason we invited you
on this time right now um well there's a
couple reasons really one you have been
pretty public with your journey uh into
full-time bug Bounty which is cool um
and I wanted to kind of interview you in
sort of brief that and see how that's
been going and also man you just have
the craziest bugs I've ever seen on the
client side it's it's really inspiring
to see um and so I'm hoping we can
debrief some of those things um but
let's let's go ahead and start at the
very beginning a very good place to
start and uh and just give me like a um
a little intro into your career path
that landed you at fulltime bug Bounty
yeah sure so hi thanks for having me so
uh my name is Yan Carlson uh so I I live
in Sweden and um I'm my career path sort
of began like a long time ago like I'm a
bit older than the average Bounty Hunter
I guess uh turning 37 now uh and so I I
was one of those kids who like doing
computers like all the time in the late
90s early 2000 uh playing games and
doing all that stuff and like I thought
that I would end up like a game
developer guess and I went into high
school doing programming and networking
and stuff like that uh but then after uh
High School I decided to quit computers
like I decided to not touch them at all
uh and I I stuck to that for about eight
years or something doing uh art studies
instead and painting and drawing and was
that like a was that like a technophobia
decision what what was that sort of like
trying to be rebellious I guess to my
friends and okay gotcha gotcha like
everyone just I mean everyone started
doing like we we started like a
collective I guess you call that like we
moved in a bunch of friends in a
apartment after high school and just
people did like whatever but most of
them just continued on with the
technical path and I decided to go down
this like artistic route instead uh but
then uh so like eight years later I when
I uh got my first kid like maybe 10
years later but uh yeah I I kind of
figured out that I had to earn some
money because I didn't really do it with
the with the Arts that's the tricky part
with art isn't it definitely about all
your your friends who went the computer
were kind of laughing then yeah yeah
exactly they had already like spent so
they were like way ahead of me then like
already like this really good positions
in tech companies and stuff uh but uh
yes I actually pretty like I got a job
at Stock's University at like the
language Department taking care of their
like uh it stuff uh and there I got to
like play with uh like doing like bash
scripting and stuff uh just to take care
of this like two rooms of computers and
then I kind of got the the Feeling Again
that this is pretty fun and I'm also
like pretty good at it and uh then maybe
like I should do it because it's like
way easier to to get the money that way
way so then I actually took
a a bachelor degree in computer science
uh so that was like I started
2018 doing that so
2021 uh during covid uh I was done with
that and I got my first job as um so I
was educated as just like a like an an
engineer to be able to do like whatever
but I ended up in this as often happened
you get like a job and they say like can
you do you know react and I was like
yeah sure sure of course give me a week
starts Googling how to write react it
was actually sort of like
that so I got that job and I so and then
I kind of got stuck in that I I switched
jobs after a year uh to where I am now
when I'm not doing full-time B bantis
but I so I've been doing like front end
work web dev stuff for three years sort
of and like I started bug bounties at
the same time uh as I started working so
um yeah they they are like
interconnected it it was interesting to
see because you you listed a in this
dock when we were kind of getting like
the all the info we need to know about
you you listed a bachelor's thesis which
mentioned gitlab which I thought was
hilarious because I'm like man this
guy's like writing a thesis on gitlab
it's no wonder that he always hacks on
it right exactly I also like kind of got
stuck on gitlab so it's uh i' I've been
uh doing like I didn't even know that
bug Bounty existed before I started that
like thesis project and since then I
just been like keep keeping at them I
guess dude it's it's great when you've
have originally you know uncover bug
Bounty and your eyes just kind of open
up to that world it's like uh I just I I
so clearly remember as well my my first
experience with with bug Bounty uh just
being at this this class uh
that I was teaching actually and Tommy
DeVos just kind of busts into this
classroom at my school and it's just
like hey bug Bounty and I'm like who are
you you know I'm like and and who are
you but also that's very
interesting um yeah I had a similar
experience because I was doing this like
ethical hacking course that I could
apply for when doing so that was the
last year of my um uh Bachelor uh in
computer science you could like pick
some courses and I picked an ethical
hacking course and during that course
which was more like a CTF thing like you
had to capture Flags in a virtual
environment uh that kind of hacking like
scanning and mapping things and finding
Flags uh but then you could get like
additional points in the course if you
found bugs uh in bug bounties so that
was my I went to hacker once actually I
could see like when I signed up I just
signed up and I got so like um kind of
like scared for the whole concept like
how could I ever like find something
here like this seems so foreign to me so
yeah that's really interesting so did
your professor your professor must have
known what bug Bonny was or whoever was
running the course yeah uh and he he was
actually so he was then later my thesis
uh guidance or what what you call it I
have no idea Joel your your thes is your
adviser whatever that's right adviser so
he actually he was part of like picking
a Target and and stuff like that so he
knew what it was definitely and so you
said you get extra points for this so
what you're saying Johan is you tanked
an exam and then you're like how do I
pass this class and he go like all right
gotta find a bug back myself into a
corner now back's against the wall help
me um so U no that that's awesome man
that that's a cool path and and I love
always hearing the ways so many people
you know end up into bug Bounty and get
to where we're at um so I want to come
back around to some of your experiences
now that you're a full-time Hunter but
first let's jump into some of these bugs
man because I was reading through this
you know some of the bugs that you
wanted to talk about on this pod and
they are awesome um really like very
cool um and this first one is a is a CSP
bypass um I guess taking an HTML
injection and and exploiting it in a
really um CSP dense environment so you
want to talk a little bit about that one
yeah uh so and this is really like my
this is where I really like Thrive yeah
when I get to do this I can
tell and like first of all like I uh
it's my the perfect situation for me as
well because I didn't really I didn't
find the bug uh myself like the
injection points I was uh contacted by
sui I guess like yeah I will not try to
pronounce people's names here but and
welcome to my world
yeah so this guy like Ross
876 yeah he he found like an injection
in where you could just like uh in an
input field in GitHub you could enter
something and you got like an error
message back and that rendered like
whatever you put there just rendered
straight back so it was like completely
unfiltered uh injection and I guess they
could have just like and they did just
report that and they would probably have
fixed it and uh done everything but you
always want to like gain gain that like
lost step so especially you I'm I'm
reading these reports and I'm seeing
like oh okay he got to last step oh no
that's not the last step there's another
oh he's going he keeps on going one more
all right yeah yeah no I was really I
was happy because I know that they
contacted some more people and I was the
only one who actually figured out how to
like bypass this feels good man on on
GitHub they have this CSP that the the
script source is just one domain so
there's nothing else there's no nonces
or like anything so you either we have
to find something on um that domain or
you're kind of screwed uh and they
actually are one of the ones that
actually also had like this uh form
action thing that I always nag about
like trying to figure out because people
miss it all the time talk to me about
that because I I had you know Joel and I
were kind of prepping for this pod and
we were talking about it's like man I
really have rarely ever seen this um so
this is like a a CSP directive that
allows you to control where a form is
being submitted to inside of a that
environment right exactly and uh so the
the strange thing is that that's not a
fetch based request uh and that means
that it's not covered by default source
so it's one of exceptions to default
source so even if you put default Source
in there it will not cover um form
action wow so so default source is only
for is that only for fetch based stuff
yeah it's only for fetch based stuff but
fetch based is like a really wide
term so it's it covers more than you
it's not just like someone using the
fetch uh framework there's is that a
descriptive term or is that a a
technical term in like it's a technical
term in the
the specification of JavaScript or and
and and how does that differentiate from
connect Source in that and like is
connect source is that going to be
different from is that also going to be
fetch based or is that I think it would
actually get blocked as well uh I think
it's only like four like really strange
things that are uh not covered by this
default Source okay and form action is
like the only like the only thing that
you can actually explore in my
experience but it's so people often miss
that and it's also like on if you go to
this regular like CSP evaluator that
everyone is using from Google that one
will not tell you about um the lack of
form action and I I had a discussion on
Twitter with this guy from Google about
that and they had their reasons like
that validator is only for like
cross-site
scripting uh is things like it's not
supposed to tell you everything about
CSP because people are using this in
like all these different ways uh but I
still think that it should have like a
mention of yeah it is called the CSP
evaluator not not the CSP eval if you
read in like the description it says
something about like try to have like a
safe um CSP for like injections or
whatever I feel like I can already hear
Becks in the background like
writing a critical thinking version of
this that looks at everything dude dude
this is a little bit of a tangent but
bevex is like really
like on top of deving in this community
man like he's building the CVSs advisor
the ssrf sheriff a bunch of kaido stuff
it's like Anyway shout out to and I know
that there there is like one other CSP
evaluator that I have been using and
that might actually catch this I I
haven't really but I usually just go for
this one as well because it's easier and
then I just look for it if it's missing
it's important too because you know
that's kind of the go-to route right if
you if you can't get scripts execution
you know you're going to be submitting
forms and trying for for uh C surfs or
you're going to be doing like autofill
password
exfiltration so it's it's I I think I
think it's a really nice directive to
have in place yeah so there's this one
called CSP validator do org that this
might be the other one you're thinking
of and it looks like it does have some
stuff mentioned about um
the uh the the form action um CLA
potentially I don't know I haven't
tested it to see like what it does but
um potentially this might also be could
I'm not sure if this is just for
validation or if this looks for sort of
the issues that you um that you that you
get surfaced with the Google CSP
validator but that could also be an
option I'm not sure but definitely worth
uh if you if you find a link to that let
us know we'll put it in the description
I will try to find it uh but it's
definitely like one it's my go-to thing
as well like if I cannot do anything
else I try to do a form and like try to
argue that you can do like out to fill
uh bugs uh some prog programs accept
that some doesn't really care but uh
it's still like a valid exploitation
path I think that you can create like a
form field even like hidden or whatever
uh in a page and it will get autofilled
and maybe even Auto submitted and
whatever and you steal credentials and
stuff so yeah Absol AB abolutely valid
method in my opinion um I also didn't
know this but the CSP evaluator itself
is actually open source on GitHub so you
want extend it if you want to extend it
and just add that functionality but they
don't want it they don't want it do you
see how how we we sniped we got Joel on
a path and now Joel has gone to a
different CSP now Joel's looking at the
code of the CSP evaluator dur by the end
of this episode I'm going to have a CSP
evaluator
written techn geek. SL CSP valuator
let's go um okay I'm sorry Yan back to
we've grilled you on CSP enough now yeah
go ahead no so one of the things that I
I wanted to do because I could inject
like arbitrary HTML right so there was
like a form in the page so the other
thing that I usually think about then is
to like just to form hijacking uh so you
could do like add these like input
elements and you on the input element
you say like form action and form so you
can like change the actions and targets
and stuff of the form and you could
potentially then if you can do that you
usually can steal like csrf tokens
because you can change the target of the
or the action of the form and you can
submit it and you get the csrf and maybe
you can like escalate from
that so it's interesting so it's on the
input element itself right yeah yeah
like like the the so it can be outside
of the form because you can also put
like a form you can point it to to which
form your uh is going to so does it take
over the entire form or does it just
take over those specific elements no it
takes over whatever you so you can you
it will add itself to the form so
everything that's already in the form
will still be there but you can change
the action and you can change the Target
and you can change some uh other stuff
cool
cool technique so the problem then was
that I couldn't um like exfiltrate it
anyhow because it was a quite strict
like form action I think you could
actually hit some uh other end points
with it I don't remember but
uh what I ended up trying to do was to
actually change the form action to like
an internal to just hijack the form to
like Target some uh internal API uh so
just you're doing like a client side U
attack instead so like changing it and
you can also add like all of these new
like input fields that will also be so
you could fill it with data that this
API route would need then so I was
really happy with that and I fired it
off and nothing happened and I was like
super confused and then I uh so this was
the the only time and the first time
I've encountered this that they had like
csrf protection per form so like each a
form they fetch the form and it has a
csrf token but it's only valid for that
path that it's uh created for do you
experiment to see if did you experiment
to see if it was like deeper than that
so like for example on a page that has
two forums you couldn't swap one csrf
from one form to another no it's
actually is it uh I think it actually
gets back to like the final bypass later
that it's actually used this like hot
wire stuff because it fetches the forms
as like a a building block and puts it
in the the page and somewhere in the
back end of this rails thing you can
enable this like csrf by perform thing
and it creates this protection for your
whole page sort of wow so that's some
sort of feature in rails I haven't
looked too deep into it I just Googled
it and figured out like Okay so this
will not work that's super
frustrating yeah uh but so so that will
lead into the actual bypass which is
like when I was like researching this I
saw that everything was nested in these
like weird uh elements that I haven't
never seen before like turbo frames um
so like I and I searched in the page for
it and there were like a lot of Turbo
frame mentions everywhere uh so I I
started Googling for that and uh found
that this is part of a a a kind of new
addition like a new framework to rails
which is called
Hotwire I don't know if it's use usable
outside of rails as well but it's sort
of like rub on Rails version of what you
talked about last week then uh the htx
thing oh it's like HTML over the wire uh
which is if you look into it it's
actually a concept that exists in all
like the big Frameworks so laravel has
its own that is called like live wire or
something and the Phoenix live view
which is uh based
on yeah whatever you call it Elixir
right and some like there are a lot of
these and most like so these ones are
actually tied to a specific like
framework and that makes them a bit
harder to exploit like htx is just a
JavaScript library and these are like
framework libraries that also have like
a small JavaScript piece that you can
hook into so a backend component and a
front end component yeah yeah
exactly yeah and uh so I can also add
that the the other two guys already had
this like drag and drop uh PC uh at this
time so the way to exploit this was
actually you you kind of like you are on
the attacker page and you drag some
image to somewhere and you drop it and
it kind of closes itself and it drops in
so it's a bit like you have to do a lot
of like user interaction but I still
think that this is uh like you encounter
this everywhere especially if you have
used like proton has their own like uh
um what do you call this like capture
thing uh that works exactly like that
you have to drag like a small puzzle
piece that's a great point so so users
are really like
uh they are used nowadays to do these
kinds of actions I think it's a valid
yeah yeah but yeah so back to the the
hot wire stuff I was let let me I'm
sorry let me interrupt and get one
clarifying Factor there so when you said
an image the way you're doing that is
you're taking the text that you want to
insert you're putting that in the alt
tag of the image and then you're
dragging it on there is that what
populates it or is it something else no
it's just JavaScript uh so the the the
the person thinks that they are dragging
an image but when you click it there's
like an JavaScript event that listens
for that and it fills your
clipboard uh or like yeah it drag keeps
yeah your drag thing it fills it with
this payload and when you release it it
will fill this uh form very nice okay
okay that makes sense yeah um and uh so
yeah so I found this hot wire stuff that
I hadn't seen before and it was it
seemed pretty simple like there there's
like three parts to it which one of them
is not really interesting for this uh
which is like this event based thing
that is it cannot cause xss in on itself
because because the events are only like
made in a connection to the back end so
it's uh it's not the same as hmx there
but other random question really quick
yeah when you're when you're discovering
this and you're going down this rabbit
hole is this through source code
analysis or is this from more of a
blackbox perspective uh I just I found
these tags uh in GitHub like in the page
Source or like the Dom uh and they
confused me because they were like
they're not regular elements so they
must mean something so that was my
thinking so when I started Googling it I
just found this uh the documentation
essentially where they described that
there existed like two concepts like a
um
uh what was the name of them again what
the turbo yeah the turbo frame and the
Turbo Stream So the turbo frame is quite
similar to the HTM mix thing that they
are you have a turbo frame with an ID in
your Dom in your page and then you make
like you tell this uh framework to make
a request to the back end and it gets
HTML back and in that response it will
look for another turbo frame that
matches the ID and it will just swap the
content uh in your Dom with the content
from this response so this the response
can contain like a lot of other stuff
but it will find the the turbo frame in
the response and it will just swap it in
place without pit reload it's
interesting that it it also works in an
environment where you're you've got like
just an inner HTML sync because I would
have thought that they would be doing
that processing sort of like on the
result of a fetch request or like in
some other way but it's it seems like
using this yeah so it's actually it has
like an observer uh and this is
something that uh I've used uh rails
also have this concept of like UJS like
U things that are like it's reacting
they have like observers that looking at
the Dom all the time like and when
there's changes they react to this
that's cool and this is something that
you can often use uh for just like
script gadgets because it will trigger
even if there's new content added to the
page so this is what happens now like if
you add a um one of these frames and
it's empty uh the system will make the
fetch to like get this content for you
and just replace it so that's what when
I realized that I could get like another
form like a more D dangerous one so I I
picked the the one where you can add
like an a SSH key to your account
because that's it's pretty good like
yeah and and you don't and then you
don't need to because you can still not
exfiltrate the response even if I could
create like an access token or whatever
I cannot get to that token because I
will not see the response because I it's
still just HTML there's no JavaScript um
but that when I add like an SSH key I
can actually get access to the account
because I I have the secret key I just
add the perfect the public thing so
that's uh yeah that's really good a good
uh attack vector and so I could add that
form so that was all nice but then that
form is added like empty and that's
where the these turbo streams come in
because the the difference between turbo
frames and turbo streams is that when
you add a turbo stream you add a
selector and you add like a template uh
an HT HTML template and when that
appears in the Dom it will look at the
the Target that you have specified like
a CSS selector and it will replace that
element that you hit uh with the
template that you you got to be kidding
me so that's so in that way you could
actually like so I first my idea was
that I first catch like I I pull down
the correct form and then I start adding
it it with like these turbo streams that
uh kind of replaces content in the form
with my SSH key and like whatever I need
to have it
U put my data on the victim's account
wow okay okay so now now we've done the
we've dragged the the image into this
sort of text box or whatever it's not an
image or or it's it's actually text you
know from the from the JS we've
triggered the HTML injection then we're
using these turbo frame turbo stream
gadgets to dynamically construct a a
arbitrary frame with the
correct uh Cerf token and I guess the
Cerf token gets loaded yeah that's yeah
that gets loaded with a turbo frame so
that's like uh by the like just coming
with the the form that you're and that's
a part of that sort of client side
server side collaboration that we were
kind of talking about with these HTML
over the wire very cool okay so how do
we how do we get it all the way are they
just going to press submit now or yeah
so there was actually like one problem
with the turbo streams is that that they
will execute as soon as they appear in
the Dom and that's true for the the
turbo frames as well M but the turbo
frame takes a while to load because it
has to fetch this data right uh so I
couldn't actually have the frames and
the streams at the same time so there I
actually had to use like an an older
like a gadget that was present in gitlab
GitHub um where they have this uh older
thing that is called like uh data
replace with which is a data attribute
from this rails the the the Legacy code
sort of like before Turbo uh and there
you can do like if you click a button it
will replace itself with whatever you
have in the data attribute uh so then I
had to put the useful
functionality yeah so I had to put the
turbo streams inside of this uh on click
thing so you had to click a button to
actually fill the form and then you had
to click another button to submit it so
it was at this point it was like a two
click thing so I because I had all of
these gadgets but you had to drag it and
then you had to click anywhere on the
page because I could fill the page with
his buttons you had to click anywhere
like two times uh so that's not like
it's not a perfect PC but it shows that
it's like you can do something right uh
so we reported that uh but I wasn't
really happy with it so I kept how did I
know and I actually so at that time I
actually reached out to William bowling
V VX another great guy to bring on the
scene okay uh so I just I know I knew
that he had done some work on GitHub
previously so uh and he was kind enough
to share like this really strange click
Gadget with me which is code that they
now they have it still on GitHub where
you can you sort of you add a fragment
and this code will try to find an
element which has that fragment as an
ATF attribute and it will click that
element for you so it's like a click
Gadget
so if you so so you you put something in
the hash and then if it's is this is
this taking advantage of that sort of
autof focus feature where you like no
it's just custom it's just listening for
on hash change okay and when it changes
it will take whatever you put in the
hash and it will look for something in
the Dom that has this exact value as
their H ref which is kind of strange I
don't really know what they use it for
but I guess it's used for actually
clicking links uh but I could also put
like an ATF on a button like there's
nothing stopping you from that if
there's there's no sanitization so I
could actually make it click buttons for
me so that was uh dude that's
clutch so that was sort of the last
thing that so now you the the final
exploitation is that you end up at this
attacker page you do the drag and drop
and then uh while you're dragging
there's a small window opening that you
don't really see and that window is like
has this
connection um like an opener connection
to the page or a parent actually you
open it so it's a parent uh and you can
that one is also attacker control so it
cannot get the content of GitHub right
but you can do I actually think that
this is quite a kind of strange behavior
from browsers because if you do if you
go to the exact you do like a location
uh equal something new uh it will load
that new page like you're allowed to do
that cross origin but if you go to the
exact same domain but you just add the
change the fragment it will not fetch
the page again it will do just like a
hash change in a Way Cross orig too yeah
yeah so it's sort of like a cross origin
connection if you have like a yeah
absolutely let me pause that there and
just reiterate that for the listeners so
if if you guys are listen listening
while you're doing dishes or doing some
you know uh task or something listen to
this part okay so what he's saying is
it's possible for you to do if I
understand correctly Johan so correct me
if I'm wrong but a window. open and if
you know the the full path of the page
you can specify a hash on that that URL
it will not refresh the page and it will
just trigger a hash change on on there
which allows you to not refresh the page
but also affect some event to be
triggered cross origin on that page is
that accurate exactly such a cool such a
cool Gadget man yeah that's really
strange Behavior actually I think like I
think it should just like always force a
refresh if you're from a a different
domain uh because it's because that you
could also use it for that sort of what
you talked about like uh U highlighting
but okay that you cannot actually do
cross Origins so that's it used to be
youf youf abused I think this exact same
functionality um cause like scroll
exactly scroll scroll fragment based um
behaviors there but but this is
different one of the things that I
really like about what you just
specified is it's you have to know the
full path which you know you could
theoretically if you opened it you know
it's very very very reasonable and then
um but if you were not to you know the
full path and you just did window.
openen hash whatever Target equals
whatever frame uh then that would not
because that would be opening up
relative to the other the page where it
came from from right is that accurate
yeah yeah so exactly so you have to
specify the full thing very odd very odd
behavior from the browsers here but so
that so that was like the final piece
that we needed to make it like a a zero
click after the dragon drop because now
I could make the two button clicks like
the Click to uh inject the turbo streams
and then the click to submit the form
could be done through this like uh hash
change events so I just had to change
the hash twice by chaining those again
so drag and drop triggers the HTML
injection injects the form triggers the
uh hash change as well and that hash
change clicks clicks a button which
injects more and another click Gadget
and then that changes the hash again and
finally clicks on the thing which will
actually submit the form yeah exactly oh
my
gosh so I was really happy with with
that one uh I wonder if this is how
people feel when I talk about mobile
bugs yeah like it's
it's amazing man you know I I love
client side stuff as well um and just
seeing this is is just spectacular so um
I'm gonna actually hold on let me see if
I can find I haven't I haven't pulled
this guy out in a while but uh is it is
it doing it is it
play nothing happened that was a fail
you know oh hold on no change it to live
hold on hold on hold on
well done y That's like in in the end I
I know I I saw someone ask something
about this on the Discord like if it's
if this was worth it for uh Ross 876
like in the beginning and I actually
think that he didn't like we we split
this uh and it still didn't really push
it high enough to become like they oh
yeah maybe we shouldn't leave out like
the final piece from GitHub which is
that you to perform these kind of
actions you have to be in like sudo mode
which if you have been using GitHub you
know that if you try to do like anything
that is like change a name of a repo or
something uh you will be asked to like
put in your password and then you're in
pseudo modood mode for like four hours
after that so you have to be in that
mode for this to work sort of uh so
that's also part of the you kind of have
to Target people at the right time if
you were to like exploit it like send
send the link at the some time in the
The Working Day or whatever couple
questions here okay one so normally when
you see this drag and drop Behavior
you're doing this into an iframe um and
in this scenario I checked the CSP on on
GitHub it's no frame ancestors of course
you know if they're taking CSP this
seriously they're not going to let their
page get iframed into any random page so
um so this was all done via window open
sort of um what's the name of that
research that came into the cool cool
research tab in uh like cross window
forgery attack sort of situation right
yeah sort of like we we actually we were
like navigating so when you're when
you're about to release it uh you have
actually you kind of just switch it out
for github's normal page so there's one
of those flows in the the the the paper
you mentioned uh the one when you like
you kind of just close the window or
switch or whatever yeah I'll link that
down below that's cross window
forgery um
by uh paos yellow there we go with the
names again um but but yeah so you're
able to switch the page and drop the the
text into the page so I really I I I
agree with GitHub here to put it like I
they put it on medium somewhere and I
think that's fine I just had a really
good time uh with the CSP bypass for me
it didn't really matter and I think we
at least double
the the
Bounty yeah and mediums on GitHub aren't
anything to SCF at either I mean GitHub
pays very well so um that's amazing to
see okay so that was one of the
questions was okay you're doing this
sort of cross window um so that's pretty
cool and the the other thing that I
wanted to kind of bring up and highlight
here is this whole concept so we talk
about gadgets on the Pod a lot right um
one of the things that we haven't talked
about quite as much is is this whole
concept of a script script Gadget within
the page in these high CSP environments
how can we convert um you know HTML
injection into something a little bit
more functional using these pieces of of
script uh that already exist uh on the
page so um it's reading through a couple
of your other pieces of of work and this
as well it it's become clear to me that
um this is one of your your this is your
jam and this is
in my mind you're you're one of the most
foremost experts on the specific sort of
Gadget of sorts um so I want you to give
us a little bit of insight into um how
exactly this how you discover these um
sort of events and obviously you can
look at like hash changes and stuff like
that so anytime we're trying to exploit
anything in these sort of environments
it's always great to like go to Global
listeners open your Dev tool go to
Global listeners look at the hash change
event and kind of see what what code is
going to be running on hash change but
looking at the the write up you passed
along to me as well there's like you
know there are events happening when
there's a specific uh class of object
being added to the Dom and like sorts of
things like that that are just way out
there so how are you finding these in
the first place in order to construct
this like beautiful
chain it's a I think probably it's quite
funny because when I started like I was
looking into so when I did my thesis way
back the the gitlab thing yeah uh we
were one of the the things that we did
then was that we downloaded like all the
disclosed reports from gitlab uh into a
spreadsheet me and my thesis partner uh
so when we started we we read like and
at that time I didn't know anything
about this like uh security or like uh
but we read like all of these reports
like one after another uh and some
things stood out and you sort of
realized that at that time at least like
William wax he was like the the main
antagonist on gitlab like he was
crushing it with RC and stuff at that
time on like EXs sence and so I just
studied his works and classic highly
highly recommend that to anyone who has
the time yeah so mimic is the sincerest
form of flattery right it's true yeah
and where from where I was coming from I
was like okay so this is how you do it
like you have to find these gadgets and
to do all of this and like because I was
starting I found my first uh cross- side
scripting like by super accident just
after um I had been doing this research
like the the thesis paper for three
months uh like trying putting payloads
everywhere and stuff like that didn't
find anything and then the summer came
and I was done with school and
everything and I had passed and
everything was fine and I just got this
uh like feeling I was at my parents uh
like having some summer vacation and I
asked thought like okay I'm going just
go in and try this I had this one
injection point that I I wanted to do
something you could name like a default
repository uh thing when some when
someone creates a project and it's it
shows you some instructions like run
these commands to create an empty
repository or whatever uh and I know
that I you could put something in there
and I just went there and just added a
super basic like script alert thing and
then it popped and I was like what I
mean I was like it can't be this easy no
no no it can't be that easy and also
like I I know that I tested this like
just a couple of weeks back and after
all of this happened and later I I
looked and the code change was just like
two weeks old so it was like super just
like by this accident that I went there
like and they actually changed the code
between me first testing it and then
testing it again wow that's wild it's
crazy but and then I I stumbled so that
popped on my local thing and then I went
to gitlab.com and I was like yeah I'm
going to get this like super awesome
high paying bug now and nothing happened
and that was my first encounter with the
CSP like I I had never heard about it
before I just opened the conso it said
like CSP blocked I was like
what from that day on Johan was
triggered anytime he saw a
CSP yeah so no but and then I went and
just uh so and so some people had
already used some of these gadgets
before on gitlab uh and then uh I found
some of my own as well uh just by
essentially like reading the source code
and like grapping for these kinds of
behaviors where it's like looking
for I I kind of went from the sync like
I found places where it did like fetch
requests I have a few reports where I
can do like these client side uh attacks
where I could create some element and it
will be replaced by some form that I can
control the path and then I can just
make like one put request to the API but
with that one request you can make
yourself an admin if it's like an admin
who clicks the link it seems to me just
from hearing that explanation and
looking at your you know hacker one
history and and that sort of thing that
you're you're just this is a function of
you being sort of growing as a hacker in
a highly cspd environment because I
think most people don't start off at
gitlab and and don't start off at you
know some of these other more hardened
targets that have these csps in place so
we're all used to oh wait you know the
the html's reflecting boom xss you know
game over but but um because you kind of
GRE grew as a hacker in this highly cspd
environment there's always that extra
step for you and it forced you to adapt
and these adaptations look like these
script gadgets and these you know sort
of far out ways to get around
CSP and and you kind of you can see that
they are also like shared between in
gitlab you can see even the
non-disclosed reports you can often see
them in their like issue tracker later
uh and you can see like these so I in
the beginning I used some of VX uh like
CSP bypasses and then I found some of my
own and then I also seen like other
people people use mine and you get like
proud like yeah way to go
like that's great and now they they
actually like just a couple of weeks ago
they they killed one of the absolutely
the best ones that was like uh because
what you want uh at you want something
that also can pass D purify right and
still work as a a script Gadget after d
purify and they had like this one that I
know like a lot of people have used it
like it I think that wax found it like 3
years ago and they have never the
details come on let's go it was just
like like a quite same kind of
functionality like you you put um an
they think at least like in the code
they thought that they were targeting a
form so they were looking for
forms uh and that a form that had like
one class and classes are like yeah you
can put that through D pufy it's wow I
thought it was going to be a data
attribute I'm not going to lie but it
was a class okay interesting yeah it was
a class so this was like a custom code
that looked for this class on the form
they called it but you could actually
put this class on anything but then it
looked for an uh an input element in
this form so the the input element
actually needed to be an input element
but the form could be anything can you
can get those through D purify input
elements are fine and forms as well uh
by default but gitlab is actually
stripping forms but so that was the good
part about this gadget because you it
didn't had V form it could be a div or
whatever that's awesome uh and then it
would look at this input element and for
some reason it would take like the title
which is also fine through d d purify
and do some sort of like
replacement uh putting it in the Dom
like whatever you put there so then you
could add like a some something that
popped and it would also then be valid
because it was coming through with like
the nons through the CSP right and like
inheriting doesn't that need to be like
um it's not in some cases it's unsafety
Val but like strict dynamic or something
like that strict Dynamic yeah
okay their CSP has strict Dynamic okay
yeah so they have nons and strict
Dynamic so it's fine to add stuff with
like a script Gadget that then adds a
script to the page wow dude that's
that's awesome and these these gadgets
are are so complex and actually I've got
a a situation I don't know um I don't
know did did mon reach out to you
recently with a a CSP bypass that he
needs on a very highly uh cspd
environment or no I don't think so okay
because I've been banging my head up
against this for a little so after this
episode I I you know I'm gonna I'm gonna
show that to you and see if we can get
it get a bypass but um yeah okay so that
that makes a lot of sense you're let me
just but it's also like it also it takes
a lot of time so it's not really
something you can do if you're just like
skimming through program
finding one of these so when I I found
some of my own where I could just like
inject this like one click stuff and I
got it through Dome purify then I know
that if I can just find like one because
you could have like an injection that is
like full but then you can also have
these ones that are actually sanitized
but if you can still so those are like
easier to find because they make that
mistake more often than just getting by
uh so so so with these like H how do we
identify these are you are you literally
just like repping through the code
looking for any sort of like um dot
whatever like clearly a class CS CSS
selector like an ID CSS selector that's
put into place and and then trying to
figure out if they're binding any
functions to these sort of classes
existing or is it just reading through
the whole thing and like what how are
you identifying these is there some
trick to this
or no I've been doing it like uh all the
different ways like uh putting a break
point at the beginning of the the
JavaScript just to see if it adds
something uh but then also just like
looking at all the places where it's
actually using like CSS selectors to get
elements uh and to see if and for for
yeah usually they have some sort of like
main functionality that's kind of like
kickstarts uh whatever all the other js
on the page is going to do and you can
kind of see there if they're like trying
to uh initialize initialize this reminds
me of a bug that I found that is of
course hacker one my two weeks is up
right now in the middle of this pod so
now I've got to like it's always on
Mondays somehow it's always in the
middle of the Pod when I'm trying to
like get into my bugs to like talk about
something but the only thing I've ever
found that is remotely similar to this
is essentially what you just mentioned
which was um hijacking selectors um for
for your your purposes so I remember in
this one scenario I believe it was a
w-based scenario um where I I I could
only get through like onclick or
something like that and it was and it
was on an element that you couldn't
click on or something and I was able to
like name it a specific ID and add a
specific ID to the element and then
later down it would say like click this
ID like this ID or whatever do click
click and it would hijack it and pop the
ex S I was like I am alleged you know
like and then you know Johan rolls up in
here with like this 16 step chain um no
so just just to just to summarize this
for the listeners as
well
um like I mentioned before this is a
really great example of how a hacker
adapts in in a different environment
right um most of us like mentioned
before are not really exposed to hyper
CSP environments and as we continue to
um move that direction in the industry
where CSP becomes more widely accepted
and more um you know just as time passes
and it gets a part of everything as
default um we're going to have to adapt
in this way and so it's really helpful
for us to look at examples like Yohan
and how he's adapted already over time
to um bypass these because we're going
to be doing a lot of Gadget searching
like this in the future so I'm going to
go ahead and and start studying up on on
all this and try to be ready for that
shift in the industry and I think it's
really um a great thing for the
community that a lot of your reports uh
are are are disclosed in and onit lab
and then you know you're doing
interviews like this where we can kind
of talk through the mentality uh because
otherwise trying to get good examples on
how to find these gadgets and that sort
of thing would be would be really tricky
um not gonna lie though I'm a little sad
there's not like some yeah just go to
the console and like Run This and like
it lists every single you know listener
for this specific thing um I mean I
think if if I
were I so this is probably one of my
problems as that I have with my like
when I do my hunting is that I'm very
unstructured and un like I there's
probably like some really good ways if
you could like sit down and just figure
out what to GP for or whatever but I'm I
really don't do that I'm just like
reading it again and again and just
coming back to the source code and just
um yeah amen that that approach always
you know that approach works well in the
beginning when we're you know sort of
developing this mentality and it gets
you through the first you know Hab many
um I'll shout shout out maton be here uh
because I know he he also does a bunch
of really interesting client side stuff
and he's shown me some um things that
you can put into the dev console that
will list a bunch of really useful um
listeners and that sort of thing so I
don't have permission to disclose it yet
so I but I know he's listening to this
episode so uh you know Matan bear go
ahead and like yeah figure out a way to
do this uh list all of these like CSS
selectors or whatever um in the source
code and then we can you know sort of
find some more gadgets like this because
it's really really interesting stuff
here um all right so that
was Johan that was the first bug we
we haven't done anything yet um tell you
what let's move let's move a little bit
I see why your reports are so long you
know that was one of the things we were
going to talk about you know um later on
in your full-time bug Bounty struggles
or whatever um but I'm starting to see
why this is happening um tell you what
let's let's go into this uh pipeline bug
yeah and let's keep this one a little
bit more brief so that we can uh get
access to some of the other goodies that
are lay on the other side of the
technical content this time around okay
yeah and I mean so this is more the the
the pipeline this this is actually my
it's my only critical finding on gitlab
uh so I'm also really proud of it like
it was one of my one of my things on my
to-do list uh to finally find like one
critical after spending I guess I had
spent two years when I found it or
something like that um and it's it kind
of represents the other part of my uh my
hunting which is not based on like uh
technical things in the browser or like
knowledge about HTML or whatever it's
like a just a business logic application
bug um so and it's also it showcases
like how I kind of work in gitlab so I
saw this report uh I have seen a lot of
reports like reading through when people
have been able to like trigger pipelines
on in gitlab as other users and I have
read them and they have Al always been
like a medium impact and I have been
like researching like there m must be
something you can do with this that it's
like higher impact than this medium like
they all that seems a little off yeah I
mean but so what you usually can do like
what people have shown as a POC is that
you can like download download source
code from other repositories with this
like if you trigger it as a victim you
can download there like maybe a private
repo or something and that's it has a
high impact but it they are staying
really strict to their like
CSP uh um no CVSs CVSs
delegation uh so and if you don't find a
way to like escalate it from only
reading stuff it will not get high
confidentiality High yeah okay um but so
so I had this dream of like one day be
able to run the pipeline as an arbitrary
user because I thought that I could do
something better with it yeah yeah and I
was lucky to see one of these fix going
out for uh this guy now I I I forgot to
look up the name of him but this other
person found a bug where you could do
this and I found a bypass to it uh and
so this is again like sort of like where
I feel most comfortable and like where I
shine is when I get some sort of like
foothold and I start to escalate it and
like show impact then when I when I feel
like it's getting really fun we talk
about this from the perspective of an
exploitation essentially like like I
think your your expertise here is an as
an exploitation somebody who can take a
little just a little just a little
something that's a little bit off you
know and turn it into some big huge
thing right um and and versus somebody
who I don't have a specific name for it
yet but somebody who finds that initial
foothold it's it's a little bit more
Recon Centric a lot of time that's
actually not not even necessarily in the
traditional sense of Recon like all
right we're scanning assets running you
know Port skins or whatever but um
somebody who spends time fingerprinting
the whole application and understanding
how all these different Pieces come
together and finds that one little piece
that's a little bit off and then you
know you can either hand it off to
somebody who's a a talented exploitation
or try to attempt that exploitation
yourself but I think um just in an
attempt to framework eyes that whole you
know the different roles of of um
hacking I think those two roles are are
pretty clear and they're they're pretty
different from other too just because
you're you're you can find a lot of you
know footholds doesn't mean you can
always take it the full distance so um
it's cool to see uh a very talented
exploitation
here yeah no so so what I had seen in
the documentation so this also like just
in the documentation I had seen that if
you trigger a pipeline it will run as
the user who triggered the pipeline so
that's all fine it will run in the so I
could only do it so I run the pipeline
as another user but in my project can
you can you give a um explanation to
what a pipeline is in this context oh
yeah so a CI CD like pipeline which is
whenever you push something to a code
base or whatever in GitHub or gitlab uh
it will more often than not trigger a
pipeline which it will build and run
some tests and whatnot okay in a
separate environment like uh in one of
these Runners which are like a sandboxed
environment somewhere but it will also
have access to a lot of like environment
variables stuff like that uh which is
interesting to get access to uh but so
the the initial bug here is that you can
run like another user but it's only in
your project so you already have access
to everything in the project so it's not
that impactful but then you can also
read some of the victims like projects
but this thing that people hadn't really
utilized before is it was like in the
end of the documentation for this
functionality it said that you could
also trigger like down
words pipelines or whatever like
creating a chain of pipelines through
different
projects ah inter you could like from
your from this pipeline you can trigger
another pipeline in another project um
and this is actually kind of locked down
now so they have fixed like the main
issue with that uh but at this time
would you have control over those
contexts or would it just like would it
just trigger it it would just trigger it
uh in Pro like you could sort of Target
the the branch I guess like you you want
to do it in the main branch uh if the
user have access there uh but what you
could so this is also like not super
impactful at that time so that's maybe
why they haven't hadn't really cared
about it before but I also like went
deeper in the documentation it also said
like yeah you can also specify some
variables to overwrite like when you do
this new trigger you could add variables
and you can also overwrite variables
that are already present in this other
project uh so then I started to look for
a gadget where this could lead to
because if you just trigger the pipeline
you have no control of like what's
happening you cannot leak anything more
or whatever um but if you can overwrite
some variables that potentially that
variable is used in like a curl command
or whatever and you can like um start
leaking stuff so that was my at Le like
the first impact I had there was that I
could add I found
uh one template so when you build the CI
pipeline in these places you often use
like a bunch of different small CI stuff
and some of them are from templates that
like gitlab provides that are like
helping you with like code quality so
that was the the the final one that I
found that a lot of people use this is
we're going to increase the code quality
a lot here I in a second I can feel
it yeah so so so that one especially was
like
uh they were doing so let's
see okay no so this one was actually
doing like secret detection so that's
good it was actually trying to detect
secrets that's great but uh but this one
was actually you could specify they are
specifying the image so like the the
docker image that the the the pipeline
is going to use that is specified
through varable to detect the okay okay
I see just just to say like so whenever
you trigger pipeline it will find the
docker image to use like as the base for
that uh that pipeline run uh and so here
I could inject whatever I could Target
it to like one of my own Docker images
and so that makes it possible to me to
do like I could run whatever code I want
now so I have like rce essentially but
in the in this kind of like pipeline en
uh but still that makes it possible to
for me to do a lot more than just like
trigger the I can now control the output
of this uh this Pipeline and I can also
read all the variables and everything
and and then just to the so the final
step for me to prove to gitlab that this
was a a critical was to just read
through their own discussions and I
found this mention of so gitlab in their
pipeline they have a variable that
contains a real access token uh that
they use to do like more like sensitive
stuff uh uh and I just saw that they
mentioned it in a bunch of places I my
report essentially was like I made this
mocked up version of this and I sent it
and I said like I pretty I'm pretty
certain that I can do this to your
environment right now and I can get this
token did you didn't even do it in prod
no no no oh man this this is where like
that's the best place to test stuff you
know I don't know I don't know yeah no
that that makes that makes sense though
yeah you want to try to respect but I I
did actually like usually I I I let
things like take its time but this time
I actually reached out to some of the
security people on Twitter so this was
of course on a Friday oh no uh so I just
reached out to them and said like I
think that this is bad um and then they
jumped on it directly and on Monday they
had the patch out well it makes sense
you know you've got a team like gitlab
you know with a highly reputable team uh
and so to to be able to
not necessarily take that all the way
and do it in prod and hand them their
access token uh you know it it you still
have a decent amount of trust that
they're gonna not do you wrong I did
actually I I did like I forked gitlab of
course so I I had like a really a
similar environment so I can prove that
it worked that's good so it was yeah so
it was my PC was like really similar to
and for sure I think
like I it'd be very rare to have a
program where you have something like
this where you say I've decided to stop
and I'm I'm telling it to you now I'm
pretty sure this does this but I want
you to check it versus going ahead and
doing it and then having them to like
deal with that aftermath I've heard of
plenty of examples of hackers where that
has not gone great yeah and I have no
idea what happens if I trigger a
pipeline maybe because it could also
trigger like a deploy or whatever and
like oh okay that makes a lot more
sense now oh you're talking about the oh
I see yeah yeah so so so in my report I
targeted like the gab's
main so yeah okay so so I had no idea
like what would happen if I did it so I
just wanted to to prove prove to them
that I have I have all the pieces to
actually run this now uh in the gitlab
main repo and so wait a second
potentially if you had leaked this token
and have access to these repos now right
right access you could have back doored
the the gitlab code base is that
accurate yeah so that's
the that is that is nasty dude that
would have been so bad I see why you
didn't do it
no no but it was it's again it's like it
proves that you if you spend the time
escalating something you can make it
like you can actually prove that it is
as bad as you you as like a Hunter
believes a lot of times when you stop
earlier uh they might not agree with you
like but if you build this scenario that
is very like plausible I think it's
easier to get it through triage very
good okay so let me let me just sort of
summarize this one really quick to get
to get get through it so first of all
you're you're triggering this pipeline
as any user because of a I I guess this
is a pipeline on your own repo because
of the fallback thing is that right
yeah so that uh exactly so there there
was this functionality that I sort of
like built upon from this earlier report
where you sort of ran some sort of U uh
just like maintenance uh thingy it's
some functionality that was broken and
and and so you're able to build upon
that functionality you're able to spoof
the the the latest committer so now you
can say Okay somebody committed to this
repo and now I'm going to delete the bot
or whatever and have it fall back to
that to that user run the pipeline and
then xfill that that token which is
associated with an arbitrary user then
you're using that token to trigger a
different pipeline by via this like
Downstream pipeline feature that you
found about in the documentation and
that will trigger a pipeline with a
specific set of variables that you
provide from your malicious Pipeline and
then that will and then using that you
find a gadget that allows you to specify
an arbitrary
Docker um file or a Docker repo or
Docker image there you go image that's
the one I was like I know there's a word
for this uh a Docker image and that that
Docker image gets pulls into the runner
executed so now you've got ex code
execution inside the the CI Pipeline on
this specific repo and then you can
exfiltrate access tokens
yes so I I sort of like skipped
the initial part there that you mention
but yeah it's
ow it was uh uh it was fun actually like
I think it's the only time when I
actually like properly celebrated
afterwards like I I went out and like
bought some flowers for my wife there
you go dude that's see that's great and
that that's actually per perfect
transition there Johan because we can
move into the full-time bug Bounty
conversation with that as well and one
of the things that Mariah and I do and
something that I've been kind of public
about on the Pod because I think it's a
really good um really good practice in
bug Bounty is doing a proper celebration
When you crush something um and and so
yeah it's good it's good to see that you
actually you actually pulled that off
and it's sweet to say that you went and
bought some flowers as your celebration
versus like mine of like buying a hot
tub or something like
that yeah yeah so so me do do you have
yeah go ahead go ahead now most of the
time I'm pretty bad at like celebrating
it's more like I get this feeling of uh
like if I I get frustrated when I fail
and when I succeed I'm just like okay
like did it move on and uh so usually I
don't get that uh in that celebration
mode unfortunately I I should do that
more often as well absolutely I would
definitely recommend that and that when
when you said often failing it actually
reminded me of something I wanted to ask
you about the Cs P bugs um these gadgets
that we talked about right the script
gadgets
um would you say that the they are often
there like is this something that often
exists like when you're presented with a
with a foothold and you need to bypass
these csps in in the complexity of this
modern era's JavaScript Frameworks and
everything that gets bundled into a page
would you say these gadgets that affect
specific you know classes or specific
data rutes would you say that they're
often in place that allow you to do what
you need to
do I think that they are probably way
more common in like big complex
applications okay uh so but I I would
say like they're probably they probably
exist in all of these the the big things
that you look at uh wow dude I wonder I
wonder how many good HTML injections
I've just like but I mean like coming
from like a Dev uh background like
myself I know that so when you're
working with these like Frameworks like
even with react or in gitlab's case they
use View and sometimes you just have
this like one piece of functionality
that doesn't really like it's too hard
to like shoe horn down in this like
framework and you just make some quick
uh like custom JavaScript on the side
that deals with some error or some like
pop up or like you're going to have like
a so one one of the ones I found on
gitlab was like this they just wanted to
show some like we're doing this new
feature popup thing and you have to get
that out like really quickly and like
building it correctly might take a lot
of time Junior Dev pushed this through
or something like that yeah yeah script
it script it together uh so definitely
like have a look in these like special
JS like the utility folders where they
they store their like custom code
because that's what's breaking like it's
way harder to get into like in react or
whatever you you there you know where to
look look for you have to look for this
like d dangerously set in in your HTML
or whatever it's called dude um very
cool very cool
stuff hey guys real quick I just wanted
to give a shout to the hacker content
team they have been absolutely killing
it the past couple months taking the
content from the podcast and condensing
it down into consumable social media
posts whether it be shorts or text posts
or whatever they've been rocking it so
uh I just wanted to give them a shout
out and let you know that they do all
sorts of cybercity content as well as
social media management they do
technical blogs they do uh comprehensive
social media management uh so if your
organization could benefit from any of
those types of services make sure you
head over to hacker content.com drop
them a line and mention the podcast when
you do to get your first month of cyber
security content marketing services for
free all right that's it let's get back
to the Pod all right so I got us a
little bit off track there jumping back
into the
uh the the scripting stuff but um let's
move now I guess a little bit more into
the fulltime book Bounty stuff so you've
been doing it now for like what two
months two months yeah two months all
right how you feeling man do you love it
is it amazing is it everything you ever
wanted it to
be it's uh it's really strange uh it's
great in some ways so like background uh
is like I decided to take to ask my job
essentially for three
months like P unpaid leave just to try
this out
uh uh and they were like they were kind
enough I can say but it's also like uh
in Sweden you actually are allowed to uh
do like up to six months of unpaid leave
to try to start a company thing really
okay that's cool very interesting so I I
don't think they could say no but but
anyhow I um yeah so the main goal has
been to see if like spending full time
on this like would it give me like a lot
of like would it enhance like my
experience of bounties money and would
it give me a lot of money would it
enhance my money it's just a plausible
way to yeah survive sorry I'm sorry go
ahead would it would it give you a lot
of or would it enhance what no but no
both uh like
would I find it because I find it really
interesting and I spend a lot of time on
it but usually like in my regular work
environment like I do my full-time work
and then I come home home and I take
care of my family and then like I spend
two hours at like night doing this and I
don't do like anything else right so
this is also like can I get back some
free time and can I still be successful
can I feel like not stressed about it
and like all of
those those are the questions that's
that you actually just read off the list
of questions that I had for you there
and I will say like um you know you've
mentioned your family and and I've got
some some uh family expansions that have
happened recently and one of the things
that I've been really grateful for
inside of that environment um you know
when family is taking up more time and
more you know investment and that sort
of thing which is great and I love um
that during the day I do have control of
that you know of control of my my things
that I'm looking at you know I can look
at things that I think are interesting
whereas before when I was single it was
like okay you know I could do my day job
and then I'd have like a couple hours
you know or more than a couple hours you
know a decent amount of time afterwards
where I could dive into these things
that I'm more interested in and I think
as your family grows and as your
responsibilities to your family get
bigger and bigger that that time sort of
shrinks and it becomes more awesome to
be able to do bug Bounty fulltime
because you can dive deep into something
you're interested during your work hours
yeah yeah and I mean I I've been
listening to like all the pods and stuff
that exists with the these people who
are doing it fulltime and like giving
tips and tricks and so just to to pref
phase this as well like I I made sure to
so I have my company now where I get my
bounties too and I had like more than
enough to pay for like my salary and
everything for these three months like
from starting out so I I would survive
like without doing this so and that's
one of the things that you have to kind
of consider when you have a family as so
as well like you have to I have to pay
like my mortgage and like all of that
stuff so so so you've set that up you've
got that in place you're and then you're
feeling pretty confident going into this
this three months of like all right
either way I'm going to be able to pay
myself so you know the bills are going
to be paid and then worse comes or worse
I can just go back to this company after
three months and and resume my normal
life so what what I what I could lose is
my self-confidence if I would not find
anything for 3 months like doing this
full-time uh that would be hard so I was
a bit nervous in the beginning because I
had like I hadn't done like anything for
January and I started doing some stuff
in February uh leading up to March then
when I was going to start so I was a bit
nervous that I had like my pipeline was
empty
and yeah yeah uh but so far it's been
I'm surprised that I'm still like in
lack of
time I get I got so much more time now
but I I don't know what I spend it on
it's just like uh still like the day
just passes so quickly and uh I still
only have like my work hours like I I
leave my kids at school and preschool at
8 in the morning and then I get back and
I start working and at like 4:00 or 5
they come back so then it's like um then
it's over uh and then maybe I do some
things uh later in the evening as well
but I've been trying
to uh also like do more of like the home
like uh the shores and stuff at home so
I haven't been working eight hours a day
maybe like six hours or something like
that yeah and and so you know in that
six hours you're you're focusing on
primarily like G lab or are have you
switched around targets much or you deep
diving one target or yeah so I actually
I had I have my like the three couple of
goals that I wrote up like on this blog
post that I never posted
uh that's the kind of stuff we' love to
get into here on the Pod tell me about
this blog post you never posted yes I I
listed some stuff like the number one
like get organized uh notes automation
templates scripts like all of that stuff
uh and then like deep dive one or two
Targets like new targets uh write three
uh blog posts and apply for a talk like
a old wasp torque or like whatever and I
I decided on these like four things
because I wanted it to be like even if I
don't find anything there should be like
an a tangible like outcome at the end um
but I have failed with like most of
these ones I love the first one is like
get or like what every Bug Hunter says
they're going to do they're like I'm GNA
have this Automation and this
automation's going to be like finding
all these bugs and I'm just going to be
like writing my notes and got my whole
like API documentation built out no no
no it doesn't work out I mean I spend so
much time like going through my like 200
Chrome tabs 200 Visual Studio code like
unsaved documents that I just create
like on the Fly that yeah uh like just
trying so I've been trying hard to get
more organized but I'm yeah I I really
fail at it this this is also one of the
things I I really I I've been talking to
the kaido team about as well is like I
think one of the niches where kaido
could really shine is this whole concept
of organization within your your your
sort of hacking um and and I think
there's a couple ways that you could go
about it obviously we need notes and
stuff like that inside of that
environment but um uh Auto naming you
know tabs trying trying to keep stuff
unified and in one place and and
assisting very cognizantly with
organization could be I think a really
big niche for um for tooling uh in this
industry because everyone struggles with
that same thing that you just mentioned
and I mean as you have seen like when
I've read some of my write up or it's
not even writeups it's a bug reports
like I spend so much time like I had
this uh day like a Monday two weeks one
week ago maybe uh I spent the whole day
writing two reports like my all the my
six hours went into that oh my goodness
dude so that's I I cannot understand
these people who are just like yes
reported that and that's me so let's
talk through that um but but before we
get to that I I want to go back and and
look at your goals so um you know
getting tools automation you know
organized that's everyone's goal in the
beginning makes sense as that one sort
of fell off the horse um deep diving a
couple targets what targets did you pick
and how is that going so that's not
going uh that well I can I picked gitlab
surprise surprise yeah uh so I I'm still
happy with what I've been doing so I've
had like two main tracks uh one has been
like deep diving some stuff uh in the
gitlab and but then I also have had this
like where I've been deep diving a topic
and applying that more broadly across
like a couple of programs so I I had one
week when I tried to learn everything I
could about these AI chat attacks M uh
and and then I just went to because
that's everywhere now so you just go uh
everywhere and you try it and I try to
focus on uh like big public programs
because I I don't I don't know the the
private invites things that those are
really not for me because I don't I
don't get any good ones I like the big
we got to fix that okay I mean the big
public ones are like they pay a lot and
they are usually like very like well
oiled that's true so and everyone has
this like Chat thing so I then I just
like jumped around on all these programs
and like tried it out and like tried to
understand so those I did like three of
these weeks in the beginning like when I
just focused on one type of bug and
really tried to like deep dive in that
uh and that was like really a really
amazing experience nice having the time
to like spend like five days doing that
instead of just like two hours here and
there yeah you can make so much more
progress when you put this time into
this and and this is something we talk
about as well a lot in bug Bounty is
like this whole concept of like yeah you
know a lot of people want to do this two
hours you know at the night or on the
weekends or something like that when
they've got time um and they get
frustrated when they don't see success
and and I I think it takes time to be
able to do it in two hours on the
weekend and it takes time to be able to
do it you know part-time um and to get
to that point and it's possible 100% to
do it you know just like you mentioned
but there's a lot of buildup that comes
up to that because your your progress is
so much slower when you're not able to
devote eight hours into deep diving a
topic um so I kind of I had this idea in
my head when starting this that I would
become this like the hacker you know
like opening up burp or kaido and just
like going to new fresh Target and like
looking at the requests and like finding
these kind of issues there uh but as it
turns out like that's probably not who I
am so I just ended up like looking at
this like super Niche uh B so the first
week I spent all this bug type like
redos like regex dos do all right very
nice and yeah so I had so that's one of
my first like payouts now they have
fixed it in the gitlab this uh actually
like a high severity bug uh in the
latest release that was really nice I
actually know somebody else who who also
goes after uh redos in in gitlab it
seems to be like a pretty common problem
in that environment um Unfortunately
they have like just they have touched it
in like at the language level so right
now like right after my week of deep
diving they actually put it out of scope
because they will fix it uh like after
the summer wow so now the The Glory Days
of uh and that's Ruby then or is that uh
yeah Ruby Ruby okay so so Ruby's regular
expression Library yeah engine has they
they fixed the the big issues with it
and they also put in like a timer that
you can set because there are still ways
to get it to uh dos but uh you they also
have this like timer option now so you
can say like anything that runs more
than like a minute just kill the process
and then it's sort of impossible to get
through gotcha okay so you deep dive
that and it's possible in some languages
but you know maybe maybe not as as much
in in Ruby no but uh it was still fun
and you did the chat chat bugs did you
find anything cool there worth sharing
or I I know we we discussed it a little
bit before and and it's a little bit
it's a little bit shallow at this point
but yeah I mean so that was kind of what
I what I found out about it is that it's
actually pretty hard to find any like
CVSs
uh like to increase it from like a low
medium sort of like you if the you have
to find programs where they actually
integrate these tool Lings uh as you
kind of did with the the Google thing or
whatever that was the bar uh chat thingy
yeah because I think a lot of the stuff
with AI is just like it's only as
powerful as they let it be right so like
it doesn't it doesn't integrate itself
in terms of
like make like you I want to do this
thing it doesn't just like magically
know how to do that right an engineer
has to say okay if they want to do this
thing then you know do XYZ on the back
end like make this API call or whatever
and so it has to be integrated to some
level like a technical right right there
it doesn't have its own agency so you
have to find those areas where yeah
definitely where you do get some agency
and I think it's like valuable to look
into because it's probably just going to
get worse before it gets better like
when everyone just integrates more and
more stuff uh into it uh so it's it's it
was like interesting but um yeah it
wasn't that
uh from what where I could tell now I I
didn't find that much like super uh
interesting functionality with it it's
fun to play with like trying to trick
this chat bot to like tell you stuff but
I think that's I think that's a common
experience you know to be honest the
most I think the biggest thing that's
going to tell you whether there's going
to be chat related bugs um is is what
what features that whole Chat thing has
in the first place cuz if you're just
chatting it's like okay well I can make
you say you know some bad word or
whatever but uh the impact yeah it was
like that it was like that that car chat
bot that was like some guy was like CH
chatting with the car dealership and got
the chat bot to say that you know would
give him this crazy low like payment
deal or whatever on the car and he was
like you know you guys have to uphold
this now or something yeah that was
pretty crazy pressing to be perfectly
honest I I was a little surprised to see
that actually happen um but okay so you
did AI chatbot you did redos um which is
a cool a cool category and then you did
oo as well right yeah that one seems a
little bit more juicy yeah that's sort
of compared to the AI stuff like o is
like the gift that keeps on giving it
really is man every time curse that
keeps on giving right every time you
look into it you find some new like Edge
case that um um
that you can like dig
into so and and then you always have to
go back to this like France Rose and
Dirty Dancing thing and you find some
new Edge case in there as well and uh so
and that research there yeah yeah
definitely and that was also like moving
jumping around between different uh
programs so I actually found some fun
bugs that I cannot really disclose uh
and that's on other programs than git so
um very nice also like so you're like
how are you feeling at this point about
like income and like um the day-to-day
life of full-time bug Bounty are you are
you enjoying it are you stressed is the
income there how's it going so I have a
problem that I I Target program uh
programs that are pretty slow like they
are they
are like have a a good reputation of
paying whenever like when they have
finally fixed it but it's um yeah so
even like gitlab can take a couple of
months before you get anything out
because they pay they pay some sometimes
at initial triage but otherwise they pay
when they fix it and it could take like
two three months four maybe if it's a
medium so I have this spread sheet now
when I have I have added like three
tables like what I've gotten paid what I
believe is like a minimum what I will
get and a maximum what I will get and
then I have this span now from like the
what could be like the possible like the
best possible outcome and then I have
this what maybe could end up that that
sounds like a very A very wise way of
doing it I I think this is one of the
things that for me took a while in bug
Bounty um because you know I'll my
normal flow is like you know clickity
clickey I'm hacking stuff oh I got it
you know you know I I popped it and then
I like get up and I run into the other
room and I tell Mariah I'm like I just
popped that 100K bug and she's like okay
just just just chill out here okay like
that's don't count your eggs before
they're in the basket or something I
forget so she's got some saying she
always says like that um but it's wise
because at the end of the day like you
don't you don't know how it's going to
turn out you know there could be
mitigating factors that you're unaware
of um that sort of thing and that can
Crush you you know I I definitely try to
not celebrate before they pay because
sometimes even like a bug that is from
in like triage state it can move to like
a duplicate or whatever like whenever
they they find it can well that's good
it seems like you've got some good
healthy healthy um you
know sort of heart saving uh boundaries
in place there so you've got this this
sheet set up and maybe most of your bugs
haven't got paid out yet um but uh
looking pretty good though it's looking
good uh I've I've been able to pay my
first two salaries which is uh great
yeah uh and that uh so that no it's it's
looking good definitely I I'm still it's
still hard for me to to understand if
this is like uh if I could do this if it
will like continue trickling bugs I
still I'm still at this uh place where I
feel like whenever I have submitted
something I kind of feel like this is
the last bik I will ever
find I become it was it was worse before
but so now I'm kind of feel like I will
eventually find something new but I
don't really know when it will happen
yeah but it also helps so targeting for
example gitlab I don't have to find that
many bugs on those kinds of programs to
actually pay my whatever like my what my
goal is right so yeah it's good it's
good when you can sort of uh it it's
helpful in the beginning when you can
couple high-paying programs with a lower
you know uh budget if you're able to
control your your expenditures for a
little while um while you're building up
that confidence and while you're
building up that that sum of money in
your in your company account that will
eventually you know pay out your salary
um so I think that's I think that's a
really Wise Way of approaching it and
how I recommend most people start bug
Bounty um full-time as as well is is
that sort of um you know smaller amounts
you know decrease the cost of living and
get that freedom back where you can work
on whatever you want every day and then
kind of move from there um are are you I
wanted to ask this as well are you
working at home do you work at your home
environment do you work from like an
office or a cafe or anything like that
or I've been so this is maybe something
that will like get to me uh if I spend
like if I do this more
that I've been sitting at home a lot
mostly because I don't like I it takes
too much time to get away somewhere and
I have my equipment here and I have my
screen and
everything so I've been sitting mostly
at home but I also went some days to a
cafe and that really helps to like clear
your mind to reset right I do I do a
similar thing it's like I got my home
base it's normally fine but sometimes I
got to like shake it and get out and
like FR freshen things up and then you
can come back to it and I think some
people they have to work at cafes or
they have to work in these co-working
environments I just like if I had to do
that every day that would be a really
big inhibitor for me I
think no but so that is I what I I have
not found any problem with getting to
work it's more I have more issues with
like structuring my time so I I kind of
have this to-do list for a day and I
know that I have to do these like four
things I have to answer some person on a
report or whatever
and then I I tell myself like in the
morning like but I if I just look a
little bit on this like don't purify
bypass thing and then like three hours
later I'm just like okay I have to do
some work now I just yeah man so that
happens a lot like I'm I'm very easily
as you have maybe seen sometimes uh nerd
snip aable as well so I spend a lot of
time doing stuff that is not really
relevant that's great my favorite kind
of hacker to collab with a nerd snable
Hacker no it's good though man because
you can deep dive the stuff that you're
really interested in and and you kind of
get focused on that um so that is
definitely a superpower in some capacity
and a hindrance in others um but I'm
excited to hear you say you know that
you you've been uh you know succeeding
with it so far and it's been it's been a
fun experiment and hopefully the rest of
those those bugs will get paid out soon
and you'll be feeling uh better about
the results uh you know that I defin
feel like the biggest problem I've had
it has been like this separation of work
and uh free time like when I go to my
day job it's very like even if I work
from home it's very obvious that I do
like this external work for someone else
and then at a certain time I just like
quit and I I do whatever now it's been
more like maybe so like my wife asks me
like are you working now or like in the
evening like are you working now or are
you not and and then I say like I'm not
real I'm just like having some fun yeah
yeah yeah and personally I think I
prefer that sort of stance on Because
unless you're doing very like singular
work where like you can spend like
dedicated chunks of time working on one
thing life doesn't really work like that
a lot of the time and so it's really
really difficult to just say like oh for
this eight hours of the day I'm just
going to not do anything except for this
one thing like you know stuff happens
stuff comes up and being able to be
flexible in that sense is really nice
where you can be like oh I I need to go
do this thing in the middle of the day
and then you come back and you sort of
ship those hours around where you
wouldn't maybe be working after 5:00 pm
normally but now you do because instead
of you know working at noon you were
doing something else and so now you need
to work later and so you know like that
I think that flexibility is just nice to
have the option even if most of the time
you do work normal hours being able to
shift stuff around and have that
flexibility is super nice it certainly
is and and I've talked about this little
sign on the on the podcast before but oh
you might have to move it over a little
bit for to show can you see it like put
it I'm just going to put it right in
front of my face but put it in the
middle yeah it says it says um ailu in
Japanese and the back side it says T and
these mean you know open for business
and closed for business and it's just
I've thought about this so many times
it's so helpful man to have these little
these little things like this that that
you can um you know put in your life
especially when you're an entrepreneur
when you're you're self-employed to to
sort of differentiate in your brain this
is work and this is play you know um
especially when it overlaps so much for
us that our hobbyists you know first in
bug Bounty and then have transitioned
into a full-time job because of the
freedom benefits and the and the um I
guess just quality of life increase so
uh there's lots of little hacks like
that that I'm sure you'll you'll develop
and this also helps with with the wife
too because you know if you're spending
so much time um you know working and and
they're trying to like respect your work
time and that sort of thing but also
like if you're just you know flitt
hacking or just like you know really
doing something from a hobby perspective
then you could say hey you want to like
go for a walk in the garden or something
like that versus distracting you from
work so I think it's helpful to have
those sort of things in place and I
actually had like that's one of my one
experience I had that was like that
surprised me that was was supposed to be
uh really
like a good thing but then it turned
into sort of a bad thing was that I I
went for a like a break like a vacation
over Easter to um to Stockholm to my my
parents with the whole family and
because I don't have like work hours now
we were just like yeah yes we just drive
on Thursday and then we came back a week
later and then it was weekend again and
all of a sudden I had like 10 days that
I hadn't really done anything and then I
started to get really stressed that it
was like this unplanned leave uh from my
own work y because I could just do it
but I didn't really think through it in
the beginning to say like I need to
still work like one or two days this
week to get like my mental in a in a
good state with this like thing that and
then you feel like you're like out of
out of the loop or out of your your
groove and stuff like that definitely it
so after that I actually had also my my
worst week during this that I didn't
find anything before like Friday
afternoon I find that like this small
like uh really low I mean this is my
biggest thing is that generally like I
think for a lot of people regardless of
Life situation it's really important to
have some sort of scheduled structured
routine that you follow like regardless
of if you're employed or whatever like
at least wake up at the same time and
like do like make a coffee like or like
have some order of events even even even
if it's not like at the same time and
stuff but just some sort of structured
routine that you can follow that helps
give you like a grounding that every day
like you either start at the same or you
do something that like helps you like
know like okay like now I can start or I
can like do the things that I need to do
today and instead of sort of just waking
up and be like what should I do today
because that's a lot I found personally
especially like very very difficult for
me for myself to stay on track if I
don't set myself like a a things that I
want to be doing and things that I I aim
to actually do and just instead if I
approach it just sort of like as it
rolls I'll find that I do a lot less and
I'm a lot less intentional with the
stuff that I'm doing yeah and I think
from my from my side as well having
experiences uh many times very similar
to what you just described of like oh
wow I accidentally just took two weeks
off or like you know 10 days off or
whatever and I'm coming back to this and
it's like okay um now I'm stressed I
think it it helps you know in those sort
of contexts to be like yeah but I just
took 10 days off you know like and I
just like man how grateful am I that I
just have that flexibility and that and
that um that ability to do that and and
reflect on that and that that that's
been really helpful for me and and
realize that that is my right as a as a
self-employed person because I'm making
trade-offs I don't have a guaranteed
income coming in right and and that
obviously um has stress associated with
it and that stress has to have a
trade-off and that trade-off I told
myself you know when I did full-time bug
Bounty was going to be the flexibility
and if I can't enjoy that flexibility
then I'm I'm it's not a good deal so you
got to like I don't know for me I was
kind of like you know like really
twisting my own arms to like enjoy it
you kind of have to learn to be
conscious about it I guess as well like
actually understanding like now I'm
going to do this and it's gonna take
time from I think a good way to think
about is like kind of like the unlimited
PTO thing that that a lot of tech
companies give right so like as a
self-employed person you basically have
unlimited pay time off well time off
let's not say hold up hold up right so
so so the real key is how do you turn
this into a limited paid time off right
because um you know at the end of the
day you're you're the one who who
payrolls and so you know finding that
balance between like the time off and
using that time off and not working
yourself to the Bone but also um making
sure that you are working and finding
you know the time to to balance work and
family and not just like woo like no
obligations let's go you know like yeah
I think it's really important the the
the the other day I took
it was it like a Tuesday or something
and I went and played pickle ball with
my friends uh you know at 1M on a
Tuesday uh my only other friends that
can go play uh pickle ball at 1 pm. on a
Tuesday and I was like wow I'm so
grateful for this because there's no one
at the pickle ball courts the weather is
beautiful you know it's just like and
it's it's what a blessing to be able to
do that and I think sort of meditating
in those moments of being like this is
why I do you know full-time book Bounty
um really helps with that and it it
sounds like you're on the path to that
as well which is really good I think I
have to do this for a longer period to
start to not feel stressed because I
only have these like The Limited three
months so I kind of want to make it
worth it but I I also I listened again
I've listened a couple of times to the
the Pod with Alex Chapman yeah and he
mentioned something that I try to like
say true to which is like he's not doing
this to get rich like the thing with
that can actually get like a lot of
money but you also have to like realize
why you are doing it so and that's true
for me as well like the point of it is
to be able to do what I find interesting
and fun and I have to remind myself of
that like so I thought that I would be
this guy like opening burp and like
finding those kinds of bugs un that's
like finding like 200 idors send in like
getting rich but that's not even what
I'm like interested in like so why would
I do that so if I find the bugs that pay
my bills then I can try to spend time on
like this really Niche things and while
doing that so like one of the points I
had was is like doing three writeups or
like blog posts and I I that kind I
stressed out about it and then I started
writing one uh that I was planning to
release like before this podcast uh and
when I was doing the write up I found a
bypass to the B
bug that I was doing right up for so
that was great like I had to scrap the
the blog post for now
uh but like
just um I really like this word the
Serendipity which is like this idea of
like if you just do stuff like the luck
comes to you like if you if you just uh
keep on doing things it will just happen
yeah and I feel like that happens to me
a lot like a lot of the bugs I found
find
are coming just like they just appear
appearing where I happen to dig at the
moment like there are things like every
yeah yeah no that's that that's a great
perspective man it seems like seems like
you got the mental for bug Bounty man
and I know I know it's different to talk
about it on a podcast um versus like
actually implementing it in your own
life and whether you can control those
um you know stressful stressful times or
whatever but I think like you said as
time passes as you get more acclimated
to that life and you become more
confident in the fact like okay I can
take two weeks off and feel out of my
element and then get back in my element
um you know diving back in and stuff
like that like you did that one time
right um where you found the bug on
Friday um I think that for me it it
hasn't gone away quite as much but it's
nice to also you know communicate with
your spouse as well and say like hey
like no you probably just all of a
sudden haven't lost your your you know
ability to do this thing that you've
been doing non-stop for the past like
five or six years you know um and have
have them remind you of that Mariah does
such a great job of that and it it it
really um really helps my mental in
those times where I'm like yeah you know
what actually I found the last buck I'm
ever gonna find ever again and I'm just
like done as a hacker now um so yeah
it's it's a holistic thing man full-time
Buck Bounty you know and it really does
help to have a great teammate as well I
I will say though like uh you know that
that's only like 50% of the battle right
so like uh the other part's inside your
own head so you you have to make sure
that like uh you know yeah you have
somebody backing you up but then when
you go and sit down the person who your
with the most is yourself and so being
able to like deal with that and cope
with that um when you're like you know
hands on keyboard is also really
important yeah it is well uh Johan
thanks so much for sharing all this
stuff man is awesome episode filled with
technical information full-time bug
Bounty information just a a quality uh
bug Bounty episode so thanks for all
that man um anything you want to shout
before we uh close this podcast
out um I always ask people that at the
end and they're not prepared
so no no not really um I mean people can
uh I try to keep my DMs and stuff open
everywhere so feel free to reach out
like uh that's one dangerous yeah yeah
it's definitely but but it's also like
with the caveat that I'm I'm really bad
at answering because I I put that on my
to-do list and it get pushed down uh all
the time but I tried at least if people
reach out with like actual questions or
like concrete like how can I do this or
whatever um I I try to uh answer them
eventually like it can take a long time
but then I do it and it can lead it can
lead to good collabs for you too like
like you mentioned and I I've said this
before on the Pod but like since we
launched this pod I've definitely made
five figures worth of bounties from
people reaching out to me saying hey
here's this bug I can't fully exploit it
and then I fully exploit it and we you
know get some percentage so um Wise Wise
shout out there Johan I see you trying
to steal some of my collabs huh I see
how it is it doesn't it it have happened
to me as well but I have one issue with
it which is uh in Sweden here we have
really like strict tax laws so it's
really hard for me to like collab if
it's not like an official collab so that
we can split it like on the platform I
don't even know how I would like uh tell
the tax authorities about some someone
just sending me like a bunch of money
and I'm saying it's like yeah that was a
collab like it it will not work so it
has to be very Like official
unfortunately uh because some programs
don't allow you to collaborate and
um should make call collaboration on by
default yeah program platform yeah yeah
100 I I don't know why this uh this is
still a thing who knows man who knows um
but yeah definitely hit you on up if
you've got any crazy CSP bypasses or
client side bugs you need exploited and
yeah I think we'll wrap it there because
there's a con uh you know construction
noises in my house that we're going to
have to cut out so someone's about to
fall through Justin ceiling any minute
all good P guys
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ct. show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there